Violetta Thijssens

With 5+ years of experience in user-related roles in a corporate environment, I have a keen eye for the user, the product and the bottom line. I am a problem-solver, storyteller, and fast learner. I love to go the extra mile for a project and my team.

+32 (0)472 24 98 32 vthijssens@hotmail.com Tisselrietweg 34, 3910 Pelt, Belgium

SKILLS

RESEARCH

- Usability Testing
- Interviews
- Online & offline Surveys
- Data Analysis
- Web Metrics
- Competitor Research
- Flow Mapping
- Requirements Analysis

DESIGN

- Prototyping
- Wireframing
- Sketching
- Drawing
- Copy Writing
- Visual Design

TECHNICAL

- Sketch
- InVision
- Axure
- Figma
- Adobe XD
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- HTML
- CSS
- SQL
- Python

COLLABORATION

- Team Player
- Communicative
- Strong Presenter
- Agile
- Project Management
- Facilitator
- Open to learning

EDUCATION

Professional Diploma in UX Design

UX DESIGN INSTITUTE & GLASGOW CALEDONIAN UNIVERISTY | COMPLETED IN 2021

Writing Course

OXFORD UNIVERSITY| COMPLETED IN 2020

Team Coach Course

SYNTRA| COMPLETED IN 2020

Diploma in Market and Social Research Practice

MARKET RESEARCH SOCIETY| COMPLETED IN 2018

MA in Business, major marketing

CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF LEUVEN COMPLETED IN 2013 GRAPHIC DESIGNER OF STUDENT UNION

CAREER SUMMARY

Business Analyst

H.ESSERS | AUG.2019-PRESENT

- Requirements analysis
- User experience
- User testing

Business Intelligence Engineer

H.ESSERS | JAN.2019-AUG.2019

- Building user-friendly reports
- Listening to user needs
- Stakeholder management

Senior Data Specialist

GFK | MAY 2018-JAN.2019

- Data analysis
- Giving presentations
- Follow-up research projects

CRM Specialist

MEDIAHUIS | OCT 2016-MAY 2018

- Web metrics analysis
- Giving presentations
- Recommending improvements to user experience

Market Research Analyst

MEDIAHUIS | AUG.2013-OCT.2016

- Usability testing and interviews
- Quantitative research
- Giving presentations



PORTFOLIO

violettathijssens.github.io

BEHENCE

behance.net/violettthijsse/